Mss.B.F865
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Dec. 21, 1850; 8x4-3/4; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. with initials. 3p. Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Refers to Leconte and Henry. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Dec. 23, 1850; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Dec. 25, 1850; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Jan. 5, 1851; 10x8; Arthur, Samuel
    Chester, A.L.S. 1p. Asks for aid in enlisting a teacher.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Jan. 7, 1851; 10x7-3/4; Kennedy, J. C. G., (Joseph Camp Griffith), 1813-1887
    Washington, L.S. 1p. 1834-1870.) Business.
  - Letter to John Fries Frazer, November 26, 1850; Campbell, H. R.
    Refers to bridges he constructed at Lake Champlain. Wants to publish account of them.
    Unlocated March 1, 2011.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n F[ries] Frazer, January 12, 1851; Campbell, H. R.
    Regarding bridges.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Jan. 16, 1851; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.p. Friendly letter. Asks a favor. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 22, 1851; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Guyot, A., (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Cambridge, Mass, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning the barometer at the Franklin institute.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Jan. 28, 1851; 10x8; Mitchel, O. M. (Ormsby MacKnight), 1809-1862
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Will lecture on astronomy.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Feb. 27, 1851; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.p. Asks for recommendation from the Franklin Institute. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, March 7, 1851; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, March 8, 1851; 7x4-1/2; Biddle, E.C. and J.
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. Presents publication.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, March 8, 1851; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Mitchel, O. M. (Ormsby MacKnight), 1809-1862
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, March 10, 1851; 10x8; Arthur, Samuel
    Chester, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Asks for help in getting a teacher.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, March 11, 1851; 8x5; Reading Railroad Company
    Printed D. filled in in ms. S.: John Tucker 1p. Invitation to view Dimpoel's steam boiler.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, April 12, 1851; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Formerly B F865.p. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, April 13, 1851; 8x5-1/4; Guyot, A., (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning barometers. Refers to Agassiz.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, April 19, 1851; 10-1/2x8; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Formerly B F865.a. Concerning the crustacean, hippa talpoidea. Concerning fossil walrus. Friendly letter. Film 1249
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, April 19, 1851; 7x4-1/2; Ewbank, Thomas, 1792-1870
    A.L.S. 2p. Enc. Business of T. R. Peale. For enclosure, see: Ewbank to Hamilton; April 25, 1849.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, April 19, 1851; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Formerly B F865.p. Friendly letter. Refers to Franklin Peale. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, April 22, 1851; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Guyot, A., (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 3p. In French. Concerning barometers.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, April 28, 1851; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Concerning the coastal survey. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, April 28, 1851; 10x7-1/2; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, May 5, 1851; 10x7-1/2; Guyot, A., (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. In French. Concerning barometers for the Smithsonian. Refers to Henry.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, July 17, 1851; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Schaeffer, Charles Frederick, 1807-1879
    A.L.S. 1p. Recommends H. S. Tarr to A. D. Bache.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Aug. 7, 1851; 10-1/2x8; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Add. is altered to read: "Care of Abner Allen... N. Jersey." Formerly B F865.a. Friendly letter. Concerning fossils and walruses. Film 1249
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Oct. 3, 1851; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S. 3p. Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Oct. 14, 1851; 10x8; Guyot, A., (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning barometers. Meteorological news. Refers to Agassiz.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Oct. 29, 1851; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Guyot, A., (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning the purchase of barometers.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Dec. 22, 1851; 11x8-1/2; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Selma, Ala., A.L.S. 2p. Friendly letter. Concerning his new post as head of a college.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n F[ries] Frazer, Stroudsburg, Aug.20, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Hamilton, William
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. General news.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Jan. 9, 1852; 6-3/4x4; Cleaveland, Charles Dexter, 1802-1869
  - Letter to Jo[h]n F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 12, 1852; 10x8; Gregory, Henry Duval, 1819-1897.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 12, 1852; 7-3/4x5; Johnston, Alexander
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning golden specks in printing.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 13, 1852; 7-1/4x5; Barnes, Albert, 1798-1870
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 17, 1852; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Justice, George M. (George Middleton), 1792-1862
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Letterpress copy. Thanks for favor.
  - Letter to John [Fries] Frazer, Jan. 24, 1852; 10x8; Tucker, George, 1775-1861
    A.L.S. 4p. Concerning colors and sight.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Feb. 16, 1852; 7-1/2x5; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    A.L.S. 3p. Formerly B F865.h. Asks him to examine a memoir on electricity. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, March 29, 1852; 7x4-1/2; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.a. Friendly letter. Refers to Prof. Henry. Film 1249
  - Letter to Jno. F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, April 13, 1852; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. Formerly B F865.p. Friendly letter. Refers to Henry. Film 1249.
  - Letter to P. N. Fitzgerald, April 19, 1852; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Chandler, Joseph Ripley, 1792-1880
    Washington, L. Copy in hand of T. R. Peale. 2p. Formerly B F865.p. Concerning T. R. Peale. On same sheet is copy of letter from P. N. Fitzgerald to Chandler; April 20, 1852. Enclosed originally in letter from T. R. Peale to Frazer; April 21, 1852. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[oseph] R. Chandler, April 20, 1852; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Fitzgerald, W. P. N. (William P. N.)
    L. Copy in hand of T. R. Peale. 2p. Formerly B F865.p. Concerning T. R. Peale. On same sheet as letter from Chandler to Fitzgerald; April 19, 1852. Enclosed originally in letter from T. R. Peale to Frazer, April 21, 1852. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, April 21, 1852; 9-1/2x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Enc. Formerly B F865.p. Friendly letter. Refers to Joseph Henry, A. D. Bache and Franklin Peale. For enclosure, see letter from Chandler to Fitzgerald; April 19, 1852. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, April 22, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington A.L.S. 3p. Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Refers to Agassiz and Henry. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, April 24, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. with initials. 1p. and add. Formerly B F865.b. Concerning T. R. Peale. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, May 29, 1852; 7-3/4x5; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 4p. Friendly letter. Refers to wines he tasted. Mentions Maine liquor law.
  - Letter to J[ohn Fries] Frazer, June 10, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Newbold, Watson
    New Columbia, N.J., A.L.S. 2p. Asks him to view a newly invented pump.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, June 23, 1852; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S. 2p. Formerly B F865.b. Concerning the University of Pennsylvania. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn Fries] Frazer, July 16, 1852; 8x5; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.a. Concerning a professorship at the University of Pennsylvania. Friendly letter. Film 1249
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], July 17, 1852; 8x5; Horsford, Eben Norton, 1818-1893
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 4p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence.. .; 1834-1870.) Recommends Gibbs for University of Pennsylvania position, Concerning a chemistry experiment.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n F[ries] Frazer, Stroudsburg, Aug. 4, 1852; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Hamilton, William
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Business for Franklin institute.
  - Note to [John Fries Frazer;]., Aug. 10, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.N.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Friendly letter. Mentions Maine liquor law. On same sheet as letter from LeConte to J.F.Frazer; Aug. 10, 1852.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Aug. 10, 1852; 10x7-3/4; LeConte, John L., (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Friendly letter. On same sheet is note from Haldeman to Frazer; [Aug. 10, 1852].
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Aug. 21, 1852; 10x8; Vethake, Henry, 1792-1866
    Bristol, A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...: 1834-1870.) University of Pennsylvania business.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Sept. 9, 1852; 10x8; McCulloch, Richard Sears, 1818-1894
    Princeton, A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Concerning an explosion. Refers to the Franklin institute.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Oct. 5, 1852; 8-1/2x6-3/4; Allen, George, 1808-1876
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) University of Pennsylvania business.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Oct. 14, 1852; 8x5; Alexander, J. H. (John Henry), 1812-1867
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 3p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Oct. 16, 1852; 7-1/2x5; Carson, Hampton L. (Hampton Lawrence), 1914-
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Asks favor.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Oct. 18, 1852; 8x5; Jones, Joel
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Concerning Haldeman as a geologist.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Oct. 19, 1852; 8x5; Alexander, J. H. (John Henry), 1812-1867
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Friendly letter. Concerning education
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Nov. 5, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Herriott, J. V.
    Canonsburg, Pa., A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834- 1870.) Asks for recommendation.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Nov. 27, 1852; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Tucker, Thomas
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Concerning porcelain making in Philadelphia by the Tuckers.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Dec. 23, 1852; 11x8-1/2; Wetherill, Charles Mayer, 1825-1871
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) chemical news and experiments.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Dec., Jan. 17, 1853; 10x8; Porter, Edward D.
    Newark, A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Asks favor.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Jan. 11, 1853; 8x5; Alexander, J. H. (John Henry), 1812-1867
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer Papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Concerning a school.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 13, 1853; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Will aid Kane. Refers to the APS and Henry. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[oh]n F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 14, 1853; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Uhler, William M.
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Will lecture.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 15, 1853; 10x8; Fry, Joseph Reese, d.1865.
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John [Fries Frazer], Jan. 16, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Cresson, John C[hapman], 1806-1876
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Friendly letter. Regarding religion.
  - Letter to John [Fries] Frazer, Jan. 18, 1853; 10x8; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from Henry, no. 6.) Formerly B F865.h. Concerning an exhibit at the A.P.S. by Dr. Kane. A.D.Bache will help it. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 26, 1853; 10x8; Genth, F. A., (Frederick Augustus), 1820-1893
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Asks favor. His experience in chemistry.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 31, 1853; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: W.S.W.Ruschenberger. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Will aid the APS in aiding Kane's polar expedition.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, March 1, 1853; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, March 14, 1853; 7-3/4x5; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    Cambridge, A.L.S.with initials. 4p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Concerning batteries.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, March 18, 1853; 8x6-3/4; Norris, Septimus
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Thanks for favor.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazier [sic], March 19, 1853; 7x4-1/2; Root, Laura
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Thank you note.
  - Letter to W. M. Gwin, March 26, 1853; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, L. 1p.and end.: "Prof J F Frazer Philadelphia" Copy. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Recommends McCulloh for a job. Enclosed originally in letter from A.D.Bache to J.F.Frazer; March 30, 1853. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], March 30, 1853; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S.with initials. 2p. Enc. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D. Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. For enclosure,, see: A.D.Bache to Gwin; March 26, 1853. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, April 5, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Chandler, T. W.
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Geology.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, April 7, 1853; 8x5; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    Raleigh, N.C., A.L.S. 4p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Concerning the telegraph. Refers to A.D.Bache.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, April 26, 1853; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to John [Fries] Frazer, May 18, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Lea, Elizabeth R.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Apologizes for letter written to Fraley
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, May 21, 1853; 8x6-1/2; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, May 24, 1853; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, May 25, 1853; 9x7-1/4; Ingersoll, Joseph R., (Joseph Reed), 1786-1868
    London, A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Introduces Charles Lyell.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n [Fries] Frazer, June 21, 1853; 7-3/4x5; Maas, Jacob
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Asks for a recommendation.
  - Letter to John [Fries] Frazer, Aug. 3, 1853; 8x5; Waters, George
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Nov. 21, 1853; 7-3/4x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Friday evening, [ca. 1863?]; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer;], 1854; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    ca. ? A.L.S.with initials. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Concerning humor in England and the U.S. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 22, 1854; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S.with initials. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Concerning the university of Pennsylvania. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Feb. 22, 1854; 8x5; Hall, James
    Albany, A.L.S. 3p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Concerning geology.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Feb. 23, 1854; 10x7-3/4; Leighton, George E.
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Will exchange natural history objects.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, March 10, 1854; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Concerning the university of Pennsylvania. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, March 11, 1854; 8x5; Alexander, J. H. (John Henry), 1812-1867
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 3p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Concerning J.P.Wetherill. Refers to A.D.Bache.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, April 16, 1854; 9-1/2x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from Peale, no. 28.) Formerly B F865.p. Friendly letter. Refers to Agassiz. Film 1249.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, May 6, 1854; 7-1/2x5; Alexander, Stephen, 1806-1883
    Princeton, A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], May 6, 1854; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J. F. Frazier [sic], June 18, 1854; 6-1/4x4; Howe, M. A. De Wolfe (Mark Antony De Wolfe), 1809-1895
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Frazer papers.) Asks that he check the enclosed for correctness of the scientific data included.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, July 11, 1854; 8x5; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Newark, Del., A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Sept. 24, 1854; 8x5; Maryland institute for the Promotion of the Mechanic Arts
    Baltimore, A.L.S.: Campbell Morfit. 2p. (see Frazer Papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Concerning his lectures on geology.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Nov. 23, 1854; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Refers to the A.P.S. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Nov. 30, 1854; 8x6-1/2; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. University of Pennsylvania business. Refers to W.B.Reed and Franklin Bache. Film 1249.
  - Note to [John Fries Frazer], Jan. 29, 1855; 8x6-1/2; Gibbs, Wolcott, 1822-1908
    New York, A.N.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Accepts invitation.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, March 8, 1855; 10x7-1/2; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from Henry, no. 7.) Formerly B F865.h. Concerning an congressional investigation of the Smithsonian institution. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, April 9, 1855; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Meigs, Charles D., (Charles Delucena), 1792-1869
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Friendly letter. Suggest leave of absence from the university.
  - Letter to [John Fries]Frazer, April 18, 1855; 10x7-3/4; University of Pennsylvania. Trustees
    A.L.S.: Caldwell K. Biddle. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Grants leave of absence.
  - Letter to J[ohn Fries] Frazer, April 23, 1855; 10x8; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from Henry, no. 10.) Concerning Frazer's trip to Europe. Asks he watch for publications for the Smithsonian. Refers to the A.P.S. Film 1249.
  - Letter to Major Lefroy, Woolwich, England, April 23, 1855; 7-1/2x5; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Frazer papers. Letters from Henry, no.8.) Formerly B F865.h. Introduces Professor Frazer of the University of Pennsylvania. Film 1249
  - Letter to J. Scott Russell, London, April 23, 1855; 8-1/2x5; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Frazer papers. Letters from Henry, no. 9.) Formerly B F865.h. Introduces Professor Frazer of the University of Pennsylvania. Film 1249.
  - Letter to Charles Babbage, London, May 8, 1855; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Florida, A.L.S. 2p.and add.: "[Favor of] Professor Frazer." (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Introduces Frazer, Refers to the University of Pennsylvania. Film 1249.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, June 19, 1855; 6-1/4x4; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Frazer papers. Correspondence...; 1834-1870.) Asks to see him.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, July 6, 1855; 7-1/2x5; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 3p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from Agassiz, no. 10.) formerly B F865.a. Friendly letter. Concerning his forthcoming publication. Film 1249
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Oct. 2, 1855; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Concerning steam boilers. Friendly letter. Refers to Agassiz. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Oct. 27, 1855; 10x8; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    A.L.S. 8p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from Henry, no. 11.) Formerly B F865.h. Concerning the Smithsonian publications, especially of the American Indians. Friendly letter. Freeman Guide 1214. Film 1249
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Nov. 23, 1855; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S.with initials. 2p. (see Frazer papers. Letters from A.D.Bache.) Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, 1855; 6-1/2x4; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873